<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-post on Personal Website</title>
    <link>/categories/blog-post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-post on Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/blog-post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy - random thoughts</title>
      <link>/post/2020/01/16/policy-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/01/16/policy-thoughts/</guid>
      <description> Immigration  “Aiutiamoli a casa loro” - many think that ODA would be the step to keep people in Africa, whereas observation of incoming economic migrants shows that those travelling are not the most destitute, but the slightly better off. Hence - in the short term - aid is likely to make more people better off so much so to become candidates for leaving (Source: ISPI podcast)   Climate change  Mckinsey Report   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open spatial data for resilience in Tanzania: Lessons learned from &#39;Dar Ramani Huria&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15_ramani-huria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15_ramani-huria/</guid>
      <description>Community Mapping For Flood Resilience “Dar Ramani Huria” (Swahili for “Dar Open Map”) is the name of a community-based mapping project in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. This project brought together international agencies, local university students and community members with the aim of putting the city’s most flood- prone areas “on the map” for the first time, an endeavor made possible by the coordinated adoption of a host of geospatial and open data tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sussidiarietà e sviluppo: l’elettricità nelle favelas dell’America Latina</title>
      <link>/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet%C3%A0-e-sviluppo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet%C3%A0-e-sviluppo/</guid>
      <description>I prepared this blog post as a reflection on the experience as a graduate student and summer intern in a NGO working in Brazil
 Uno dei temi che hanno maggiormente animato il recente dibattito sulla cooperazione allo sviluppo è la critica rivolta a governi e istituzioni multilaterali (Banca Mondiale, Fondo Monetario Internazionale e varie agenzie ONU in primis), di gestire gli aiuti ai paesi in via di sviluppo in modo arbitrario, assitenzialista e ultimamente inefficace (in sintesi con un approccio top-down).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>