<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis for Green Card processing time</title>
      <link>/post/2019/07/07/green-card-processing-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/07/07/green-card-processing-time/</guid>
      <description> This short project investigates whether the Trump administration has slowed down the labor certification &amp;amp; green card application process for foreign workers. The analysis relies on DOL/OFLC and USCIS open data.
Results  Short Article Code on Github   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open spatial data for resilience in Tanzania: Lessons learned from &#39;Dar Ramani Huria&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15_ramani-huria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15_ramani-huria/</guid>
      <description>Community Mapping For Flood Resilience “Dar Ramani Huria” (Swahili for “Dar Open Map”) is the name of a community-based mapping project in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. This project brought together international agencies, local university students and community members with the aim of putting the city’s most flood- prone areas “on the map” for the first time, an endeavor made possible by the coordinated adoption of a host of geospatial and open data tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sussidiarietà e sviluppo: l’elettricità nelle favelas dell’America Latina</title>
      <link>/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet%C3%A0-e-sviluppo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet%C3%A0-e-sviluppo/</guid>
      <description>I prepared this blog post as a reflection on the experience as a graduate student and summer intern in a NGO working in Brazil
 Uno dei temi che hanno maggiormente animato il recente dibattito sulla cooperazione allo sviluppo è la critica rivolta a governi e istituzioni multilaterali (Banca Mondiale, Fondo Monetario Internazionale e varie agenzie ONU in primis), di gestire gli aiuti ai paesi in via di sviluppo in modo arbitrario, assitenzialista e ultimamente inefficace (in sintesi con un approccio top-down).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog is intended as a place to collect notes-to-self, R code snippets, inspiring ideas, and side-projects that stay tenaciously planted on my &amp;ldquo;To-Do&amp;rdquo; list.
Bio My name is Luisa M. Mimmi. I was born and raised in 🇮🇹, although I have been in the 🇺🇸 for 10+ years, based in Washington, DC.
When I am not procrastinating, or chasing a decent espresso, I am a consultant for multi-lateral development banks, passionate about using data to understand and tackle various dimensions of infrastructure poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV (English and Italian)</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description> Here is a link to my (long) CV: 3pg CV - English. Here is a link to my (long) CV: 4pg CV - Italian.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/wrong_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/wrong_index/</guid>
      <description> --  By Leonora Faraone   --  Apri la mente a quel ch’io ti paleso
e fermalvi entro; ché non fa scïenza,
sanza lo ritenere, avere inteso.
(Dante Alighieri, Divina Commedia, Paradiso V, 40-42)
 NOTES, R PROJECTS, etc. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>