<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Personal Website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>G20 - collection of thoughts</title>
      <link>/post/2020/01/16/g20-collection-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/01/16/g20-collection-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description> Immigration  “Aiutiamoli a casa loro” - many think that ODA would be the step to keep people in Africa, whereas observation of incoming economic migrants shows that those travelling are not the most destitute, but the slightly better off. Hence - in the short term - aid is likely to make more people better off so much so to become candidates for leaving (Source: ISPI podcast)   Climate change  Mckinsey Report   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(in progress) Survey of water suppliers in Brazil</title>
      <link>/post/2019/10/22/green-card-processing-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/10/22/green-card-processing-time/</guid>
      <description>Purpose of the study The survey is part of a larger effort to collect original data in preparation of the publication “Development in America” 2020 that will focus on Infrastructure (Energy, Water and Transportation) sector in LAC.
 Creators This page was created by Luisa M. Mimmi (Research Fellow - consultant at IADB) but builds on data collected by various IADB colleagues and partner organizations.
 Acknowledgements  This survey is sponsored by the Interamerican Development Bank (IADB), Water Division, Knowledge Team WSA Knowledge, where I work as a consultant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Green Card processing time</title>
      <link>/post/2019/07/07/green-card-processing-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/07/07/green-card-processing-time/</guid>
      <description> This short project investigates whether the Trump administration has slowed down the labor certification &amp;amp; green card application process for foreign workers. The analysis relies on DOL/OFLC and USCIS open data.
Results  Short Article Code on Github   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYE fundraising data analysis </title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/14/nye-fundraising-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/14/nye-fundraising-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Since March 2018, I have worked part-time as a Pro-Bono Fundraising Data Analyst for the nonprofit organization New York Encounter. I performed several ETL tasks –via SQL-based data transformations and R programming– to set up the integration of data that existed in separate and disconnected platforms. Namely, the Nonprofit had informations on donors and attendees on SendGrid, donations recorded via Square and miscellaneous other information in Salesforce. After cleaning and merging such information, I performed an initial explorative characterization of the Nonprofit private donors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkdIn Data: competitivity of cities</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/15/linkdin-data-competitivity-of-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/15/linkdin-data-competitivity-of-cities/</guid>
      <description> This mini-study project was a take-home test I completed in winter 2018 as part of a job interview for a consultancy with IFC (in collaboration with LinkedIn). I used it as an opportunity to refresh some R programming and learn to use the xaringan package to make html presentations.
Results  Slides (xaringan)
 Code on Github
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Development Indicator: life expectancy analysis </title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/20/world-development-indicator-life-expectancy-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/20/world-development-indicator-life-expectancy-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This mini-study project was an exercise to learn how to use the World Bank’s API for the World Development Indicator (WDI) repository.
In this study, I explore the indicator Life expectancy at birth and I also do some comparative analisys using other indicators that I expect to be highly correlated with life expectancy: namely GDP and the status of Fragile and conflict affected situations (FCS).
 In order to flag the individual countries that are classified as FCS, I used the World Bank list of economies (as of June 2017) found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open spatial data for resilience in Tanzania: Lessons learned from &#39;Dar Ramani Huria&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15_ramani-huria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15_ramani-huria/</guid>
      <description>Community Mapping For Flood Resilience “Dar Ramani Huria” (Swahili for “Dar Open Map”) is the name of a community-based mapping project in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. This project brought together international agencies, local university students and community members with the aim of putting the city’s most flood- prone areas “on the map” for the first time, an endeavor made possible by the coordinated adoption of a host of geospatial and open data tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sussidiarietà e sviluppo: l’elettricità nelle favelas dell’America Latina</title>
      <link>/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet%C3%A0-e-sviluppo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet%C3%A0-e-sviluppo/</guid>
      <description>I prepared this blog post as a reflection on the experience as a graduate student and summer intern in a NGO working in Brazil
 Uno dei temi che hanno maggiormente animato il recente dibattito sulla cooperazione allo sviluppo è la critica rivolta a governi e istituzioni multilaterali (Banca Mondiale, Fondo Monetario Internazionale e varie agenzie ONU in primis), di gestire gli aiuti ai paesi in via di sviluppo in modo arbitrario, assitenzialista e ultimamente inefficace (in sintesi con un approccio top-down).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to useful R resources</title>
      <link>/post/2000/09/29/links-to-useful-r-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2000/09/29/links-to-useful-r-resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are some useful links and resources for R programming.
General  Rstudio Community: forum and discussions organized by macro-topic. Rseek: a sort of wiki R page! From rstudioconf2019: a collection of R resources by @littlemissdata Cheatsheets: self-explanatory WTF.. or &amp;ldquo;What They Forgot to Teach You About R&amp;rdquo; 😉 Another life-changing guide from Jenny Bryan Google&amp;rsquo;s R Style Guide  Project Management  Best Practices Handling Packages R-Bloggers blog (scroll to) reference: collection of links&amp;hellip; analytical work reproducibly using R: Pre-print article Karl Broman slides Joris Muller&amp;rsquo;s Blog on The &amp;ldquo;ten simple rules for reproducible computational research&amp;rdquo; in R Joris Muller&amp;rsquo;s Blog on A basic reproducible data analysis workflow - principles  R studio TERMINAL  Great post Using rstudio-terminal/ More on Using the RStudio Terminal  DATABASES  Databases using R RStudio list  API &amp;amp; R  Amanda Gadrow Resources Saving tokens Various Ways Saving tokens WTF&amp;hellip; to tell you  ggplot2 &amp;amp; GRAPHS  Great line by line tutorial ggplot flipbook Modern Dive Chapter Grammar of Graphics  Table Packages to discover  DataExplorer EDA, See github Formattable Tables, See more info table1 Tables, See more info ggstatsplot Graphs, See more info Extension of ggplot2 package for creating graphics with details from statistical tests included in the plots themselves and targeted primarily at behavioral sciences community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog is intended as a place to collect notes-to-self, R code snippets, inspiring ideas, and side-projects that stay tenaciously planted on my &amp;ldquo;To-Do&amp;rdquo; list.
whoami My name is Luisa M. Mimmi. I was born and raised in 🇮🇹, although I have been in the 🇺🇸 for the last 10+ years, based in Washington, DC.
When I am not procrastinating, or chasing a decent espresso, I am a consultant for multi-lateral development banks, passionate about using data to understand and tackle various dimensions of infrastructure poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV (English and Italian)</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description> Here is a link to CV in English. Here is a link to CV in: Italian.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>